When an institution moves a large block of bonds, it cannot simply post it — the moment the order and the competing bids are visible, the market front-runs it.
Bisik is a confidential over-the-counter desk built natively on Canton.
You whisper quotes, and the market hears nothing.
We have built this same product four times before, on four different chains.
Every time, most of the work was cryptography fighting the ledger. On Canton, that machinery disappears.
Let me show you the desk itself, running against a live Canton ledger.
These three columns are one ledger seen by three parties: a buyer and two competing dealers.
Each column shows only what that party’s own node actually received.
The buyer opens a request for quote: a thirty-year treasury, one thousand units, paid in tokenised dollars.
The market never sees this. Only the invited dealers do.
Dealer A now sees the request, and answers with a sealed quote — four million, two hundred and ten thousand.
Watch what happens on the right.
Dealer B's column is empty. Not a masked row. Not a hidden-bid placeholder. Nothing at all.
Dealer A's quote was never transmitted to Dealer B's node. That is not the interface hiding it — it is the ledger never sending it.
Dealer B quotes too — four million, two hundred and fifty thousand — completely blind to its rival.
The buyer now holds both sealed quotes. Neither dealer can see the other.
Either side can reveal one sealed quote to a regulator on demand — never to a rival, never in public.
Now the buyer awards. The cheapest dealer wins — but is paid the second price, four million two hundred and fifty thousand.
Cash and bond move in a single atomic transaction: both legs, or neither.
You don’t have to trust the privacy. This view queries what each node actually holds:
each dealer sees only its own quote, and the regulator sees nothing before settlement.
This is what institutions actually need. A public exchange proves best execution against a visible order book.
Bisik has no order book — and still proves it, from the sealed asks disclosed to the regulator.
The same desk runs autonomously: two market-maker agents quote blind to each other, a buyer agent awards, and a real trade settles on Devnet at the second price — with no human in the pricing loop.
None of this is a mock-up. Forty-one settled trades, five atomic baskets and sixteen best-execution attestations are live on Canton Devnet right now.
Bisik — the confidential OTC desk that finally didn’t need a cryptography stack, because Canton already is one.